As the COVID-19 pandemic enters its third year, the world has transitioned to living with
awareness of the coronavirus.
China, however, continues to pursue its zero-COVID policy to eliminate the virus completely
by imposing restrictive measures on its citizens.
But highly contagious new strains of the virus have made containing it a difficult task.
The result is a perpetual cycle in and out of strength regulations.
Even going shopping or to work becomes an ordeal.
We followed three months in the lives of people in the capital of Beijing, who have been deeply affected by the zero-covid policy.
A residential district in Northern Beijing.
Freelance journalist Liu Bowen is considering moving to the area and has come to look at rental properties.
Liu currently lives in Yanjiao, a residential town located in Hubei Province just to the east
of Beijing.
Due to the zero COVID policy, he's been stuck in Beijing since the border is closed.
His searches can find two old apartments.
He can't afford to pay for any better.
Liu pays 270 US dollars a month for his apartment in Yanjiao.
But this room is more than three times that, at nearly $1,000.
He scours the city for an even slightly more affordable location.
Li-yu has a reason for seeking to move into Beijing despite the major price increase.
But because of the construction, we can't go there.
The river spanning the border between Yen Zhao and Beijing
is traversed by a large bridge.
When there's an infection on either side,
it's sealed off to impede travel.
After a long day examining properties,
Liu heads to his parents' home within Beijing.
He's often had to stay with them
when the border suddenly closed
while he was on the job in the city.
For example, this is the second time.
In the last year, I remember the year I was born,
the year 21,
the actual makeup was in the past.
It was also a makeup makeup.
When I was not in a hospital,
it was also a makeup makeup.
Hubei Province and Circles Beijing.
No matter where on its expanse infection is detected,
roads are immediately sealed to protect the capital.
As a result,
residents of Yen Zhao were blocked from entering Beijing.
The harsh policy to stamp out the pandemic
his head in unending effect on the lives of locals.
As a journalist, Liu seeks to convey this reality
as it unfolds.
His latest article, posted in March 2022,
featured the border between Beijing and Yangjao.
Oh, this is the day you've been taking photos.
No.
Liu shows a photograph he took on March 18.
An infection found in Hubei had closed the borders.
On the Beijing side, a long line of people
waited at a checkpoint in order to return home to Yen Zhao.
It was a massive snowfall.
The men and women waiting to make it back home
were at the mercy of the blizzard.
Leo detailed and recorded their experiences in his article.
Some said they've been waiting in the snow for six hours.
As it was, only their families had heard
these voices of anger, sadness, and resignation.
There were even reports of Yen Zhao citizens
driven by the solitude to take their own lives.
As the serial COVID policy pushes on despite the misgivings of many people, Liu continues to document their applied.
This office building stands in East Beijing. Liu pays a visit to a company that's one of
the tenants there. The Zero COVID policy has caused major business difficulties for
them recently. Inside, the office is quiet. Many of its employees who live outside the
city are now unable to come in for work. The company is a joint venture with a German
machine tool manufacturer.
Its president, Chen Zhengpeng, was interviewed by Liu.
Every time the border's closed, employees are kept away from their work.
How long each closure will last is anyone's guess.
I've been watching this for 14 days.
I haven't seen it for 14 days.
I've never seen anything like this before.
I hope I can make a video about it.
I've been watching it for 12 years.
I've been watching it for a long time.
I've never seen it before.
Although the company hasn't encountered a single infection, their business is frozen
in place.
PCR tests are available all over Beijing,
with long lines of people waiting to check for infection.
Without negative certification,
they aren't allowed to use public transportation,
or even enter supermarkets, restaurants, or hospitals.
The testing centers become a gateway to the most basic social functions.
However, test results are valid for as little as 48 hours.
Some tests take up to half a day to return results,
making constant repetition of the testing process a necessity.
From infants to the elderly, no ages are exempt from the rules.
All Chinese citizens are essentially forced to use a pair of apps known as
Activity Code and Health Code. Activity Code uses GPS to report the places a person
has visited in the last 14 days, allowing the government to monitor their location.
Health code uses AI to examine activity and PCR testing history to give an overall rating to the user's status.
Green allows travel to unrestricted areas. Yellow requires observation at home, and red means quarantine at a designated facility.
This is what home observation looks like. A notice is placed across the door. One person returned from Shanghai to Beijing.
Excursion and outside contact prohibited.
Report all violations.
A censoring camera are also attached to the door to detected opening.
The resident is placed under 24-hour surveillance.
The neighborhood of Tian Tung Yuan is at the heart of Beijing.
It's a large housing complex home to over 500,000 people.
It's been placed under quarantine since an infection was discovered.
Forbidding the entry of all but residents who undergo strict checks when they pass through.
With the whole complex being sealed off, an unspectacle can be found just outside.
Packages line the streets, left by delivery companies for the residents to pick up themselves.
At this area inside, a number of stores and restaurants operate.
This restaurant sells the popular noodles of Hunan province.
There is a single customer to be found.
Eating there has been forbidden, with only takeout available.
Even more bad news is on the way.
Every time a new infection is found,
The production is found, it leads to a large scale quarantine.
Even with the drop in sales, they have no choice but to soldier on.
The store stays open at night as well, waiting for customers that might never come.
During the day, they had less than ten customers.
From the night shift, they expect even fewer.
We can see the people are suffering from the fever and the fever of the people in the past.
There are a lot of people who are suffering from that.
How long will they eat today?
The speed to the eastern edge of Beijing are packed with people on their way home.
They're all headed for Yanzhang.
The on the checkpoint is the bridge connecting Beijing with Yenjiang.
After being sealed off for three weeks, the border has finally been reopened.
The machine tool manufacturer is able to resume operations.
Its employees who live outside the city can now meet face-to-face again.
Company President Chen gathers the staff for a frank discussion.
There's no telling when another lockdown might start.
To make sure they retain enough workers, some sleep at the office after work.
Chen receives a phone call.
One of the engineers on a business trip is stuck during a border closure.
He can't change locations to reach their waiting client.
When did you get married?
Did you have a little news?
I was just thinking about it.
I just thought about it.
As expected, the client was upset. They were disappointed that the work would be delayed.
What do you mean?
We were so busy that we couldn't get up.
We were not just in a few places.
We were in danger.
But now, we are in a very difficult position.
We are not doing anything.
We have been in a very big situation.
We have been in a very difficult situation.
Because you don't do anything to prevent this.
Journalist Liu Bowen
chose to rent a room in this apartment building.
The lockdown was lifted in time for him to finally make his move.
Now even if the borders of Beijing are closed, he won't be separated from his wife and son.
However, the apartment does have its drawbacks.
A major event happened in his work as well.
His article on the border between Beijing and Yen Zhao
a mass detention, gathering over 5,000 comments.
It makes me sad.
Our society should show more kindness and warmth.
We all have mortgages and families to support.
I wish it wouldn't cost us our jobs.
But the article attracted the government's attention,
and Liu was forced to delete it.
A few days after posting the article,
Liu was brought in to the police department for a warning.
But he made a surprising discovery there.
A couple of people saw it.
Liu said,
A few days after posting the article, Liu was brought into the police department for a warning.
But he made a surprising discovery there.
Liu is gripped with a sense of resentment that his article won't be enough to change the reality around him.
In the end, you can't change the government's policy.
You can't change the policy.
You can only use it.
On April 28, an infection was discovered within Beijing,
leading to border closures that continued all through May.
Then on June 1, a conflict erupted on the border of Beijing in Yangzhou.
citizens attempting to enter Beijing clashed with police officers.
On that same day, the government announced that they would loosen restrictions.
From June 6, the restrictions were lifted in most districts of Beijing.
The machine tools manufacturer could finally meet with its employees.
For the first time in over a month, they assembled for work.
United again, the workers enjoy their time together. But none of them can predict when
And they might be separated again.
On the same day, the restrictions were lifted from restaurants in Beijing.
But in Tian Tung, UN, because two infections were discovered nearby, dining in is still
forbidden.
The noodle shop continues to desperately cling to life.
As citizens search for ways to survive, China's zero-Covid policy remains looming overhead.